<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classification on Oday Mourad</title>
    <link>https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/tags/classification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classification on Oday Mourad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/tags/classification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/post/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/post/project5/</guid>
      <description>Problem Overview:
EEE-CIS works across a variety of AI and machine learning areas.
We have a binary classification problem with a heavy imbalance which is an inherent property of such problems.
Dataset: The data comes from Vesta&amp;rsquo;s real-world e-commerce transactions and contains a wide range of features from device type to product features.
Target: predicting the probability that an online transaction is fraudulent.
Project Overview:
Discovering the data and applying Exploratory Data Analysis to extract some patterns related to if a transaction fraud or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Natural Language Processing with Disaster Tweets</title>
      <link>https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/post/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/post/project4/</guid>
      <description>Dataset: more than 10,000 real tweets.
Target: Predict which tweets are talking about disaster and which are not.
Project Overview:
Discovering the data and applying Exploratory Data Analysis to extract some patterns related to if a tweet is about disaster or not.
Full data cleaning (remove: stop words, urls, emojies, &amp;hellip;.).
Correcting spelling using textblob.
applying Text vectorization using Glove.
Tokenizing each tweet and building the embedding matrix.
Building deep neural network model using Lstm to start predicting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Spaceship Titanic Survived Prediction</title>
      <link>https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/post/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/post/project3/</guid>
      <description>Problem Overview:
The Spaceship Titanic was an interstellar passenger liner launched a month ago. With almost 13,000 passengers on board, the vessel set out on its maiden voyage transporting emigrants from our solar system to three newly habitable exoplanets orbiting nearby stars.
While rounding Alpha Centauri en route to its first destination—the torrid 55 Cancri E—the unwary Spaceship Titanic collided with a spacetime anomaly hidden within a dust cloud. Sadly, it met a similar fate as its namesake from 1000 years before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Titanic Survived Prediction</title>
      <link>https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/post/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://odaymourad.github.io/Oday_Portfolio/post/project2/</guid>
      <description>Problem Overview:
The sinking of the Titanic is one of the most infamous shipwrecks in history.
On April 15, 1912, during her maiden voyage, the widely considered “unsinkable” RMS Titanic sank after colliding with an iceberg. Unfortunately, there weren’t enough lifeboats for everyone onboard, resulting in the death of 1502 out of 2224 passengers and crew.
While there was some element of luck involved in surviving, it seems some groups of people were more likely to survive than others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
